Maksim Popov

London, N4 1RU, UK exactlyy@gmail.com • 07412379097 • LinkedIn: Maksim Popov



PERSONAL SUMMARY

HR specialist with skills in: Onboarding, Employee Lifecycle, Data maintenance and Tech skills. My focus is keeping people information secure, up to date, and easy achievable for the organization. Combining experience, HR degree and technical skills, I like to change long and complicated processes into intuitively simple and more efficient. I like to evaluate processes, think out of the box, because that can move business forward to become more competitive and improves reputation amongst stakeholders.

KEY SKILLS

- Workday, Salesforce, Slack
- Strong communication
- Organisational skills
- Proven problem-solving skills
- "Get the job done" attitude
- Attention to detail
- Excellent IT skills (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook)

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

CODE INSTITUTE | 10/2023 - PRESENT | Full Stack Software Developer | Bootcamp course

MSc in International Business with Human Resource Management | 02/2020 -2022 | Ulster University | London

Qualification is equivalent to CIPD level 7

[Distinction]

Relevant Modules: Managing and Leading People in International Organisations, International HRM, Global strategy

BA Business Management |02/2016-10/2019 | Roehampton Business University | London

[2:1 Honours]

Relevant Modules: Managing People and Careers, Cross-cultural Management, Business Ethics and Responsible Management, Analysing Information, Data for Problem Solving

Personal Licence Certificate BIIAB Level 2

BA Business and Management | 10/2004 - 06/2008 | ECOMAN University | Tallinn

BA Manufacturing Management (Distance learning) | 10/2004 - 06/2008 | INZEKON University | St. Petersburg

Certificate of IT | 09/2002 - 06/2003 | IT College | Tallinn

Graduated | College of Retail and Service | 09/1998 - 05/2002 | Tallinn

WORK EXPERIENCE

PEABODY - WESTMINSTER

PEOPLE OPERATIONS ASSISTANT (FEB 2024 - PRESENT)

- Onboarding process for New Starters
- Personal Data "maintenance and GDPR"
- Experian, DBS and RTW check.

OCADO - HATFIELD

HR ADMIN (SEP 2021 - FEB 2024)

- Management of the HR Systems i.e. Workday. Ensuring data is accurate and up to date
- Interviewing and "candidate selection" process.
- Sensitive information management, following GDPR processes and supporting legal requirements within the business.
- Working as part of a large HR Shared Service Team and supporting day-to-day queries across multiple missions, locations, and organizations. [recruiting, onboarding, employee relationships, employee life cycle]
- Managing administration tasks and reports, collaborating with payroll to solve various issues.
- Payroll support by monitoring and initiating administrative changes associated with long-term absences.
- Responsible for completing any other duties that may be required for the proper performance of the business.
- Create, update and distribute HR-related reports to key stakeholders
- Supporting recruiters within the Talent Acquisition program and team training.

MERE RETAIL - ERITH

BUYING ASSISTANT (MARCH 2021 – AUGUST 2021)

- Co-operation with internal and external stakeholders.
- Building relationships with suppliers, search for the best optimisation processes and solving complex problems
- Replying emails, calls, organising zoom/office meetings with new clients

Key Achievements

- Understanding of the market, weekly research and analysis.
- Leading and managing operational processes between stores and suppliers
- ❖ Work with documents such as: contracts, amendments, MS World, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, Adobe, 1C.
- Time management and organisational skills.

VODAFONE – Notting Hill Gate

Assistant HR Manager (July 2016 – October 2018)

- Supporting manager with selection, interviewing and recruitment processes.
- Assisting and using Kronos HRM software.
- Support with staff training.
- Responded to all incoming calls regarding general inquiries in a courteous manner and delivered required information.
- Maintained customer records in compliance with GDPR

Key Achievements:

- Improved professional capabilities and work efficiency of new staff members through providing training and assistance.
- In 2016 received a reward and acknowledgement from senior management for delivering exceptional customer service.

VILLE FOOD LTD - Canning Town

Director and CEO (January 2015 – May 2016)

- Recruitment, managing people and providing training to staff
- Coaching and up-skill managers at all levels on employment law, HR policy, procedure, and implementing on practice.
- Stock management and updating the product database.
- Accounting and Payroll

Key Achievements:

- KPI Plan, successfully meeting and surpassing sales targets in 2015.
- Enhanced operational efficacy by designing an efficient delivery model and logistic routes for the company's delivery.
- Established targets for employees and provided high-quality support to staff in reaching 90% of targets.
- In one year, I built relationships with more than 200 clients through cold calls

COMPASS GROUP - St. Pauls

Team Supervisor (October 2012 – June 2014)

- Checked and controlled products quality in accordance with company standards.
- Handled a wide range of HR tasks, such as administering staff induction and providing training to new starters.

Key Achievements:

- Attained top-level customer feedback and rewarded for delivering high-level customer service, including resolving issues, developing superior client relationships, and responding to inquiries for attaining top-level customer feedback.
- Accomplishment of day-to-day objectives between 85 to 120 % through outperforming all assigned tasks.

MAXIMA EESTI - Estonia

Assistant Manager (June 2008 – October 2011)

- SAP program, transactions, search of information and product names in the system.
- Negotiated and managed suppliers rates, special deals and delivery dates. Dealt with mainline suppliers, such as Unilever, Captain Nemo, Uvic, and others.
- Made orders for the shops and tracked price changes in the system, such as discounts, special offers, and correct payment. Gained exceptional brands knowledge, business procedures, current prices in the local market, and sellers.
- Usage of Pivot Tables and Excel to sort information and effectiveness of the business.

Key Achievements:

- Application of analytical skills, knowledge of financial analysis, reports. Weekly performed competitiveness analysis.
- Build strong business relationships with clients.

INTERESTS

* Gym, Skiing, Health, Traveling, Self-Development and Optimism.